Guide to the David Epel Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
David Epel papers
circa 1959-2009
SC0977
Epel, David, 1937-
22 Linear feet
The collection consists of the professional papers of Dr. David Epel, including correspondence with colleagues; administrative files from his tenure as acting dean of Stanford Universty's Hopkins Marine Station; lab notebooks; research files and drafts of published work; files on grants from the National Institute of Health, the National Science Foundation, and other funding sources; files on conferences attended; and lecture notes, syllabi, examples of student work, and other materials from courses taught by Epel.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
This collection was given to the Stanford University Archives by David Epel in 2009.
Information about Access
Files in series 10 are restricted until January 1, 2060. Otherwise the collection is open for research; materials must be requested at least 48 hours in advance of intended use. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Biographical/Historical note
David Epel received his Ph.D. in biology from the University of California, Berkeley, where he studied under Daniel Mazia. He joined Stanford University's Hopkins Marine Station in 1965. In 1970, he accepted a position at the University of California San Diego's Scripps Institute of Oceanography. He returned to Hopkins in 1977, where he remained until his retirement as Professor Emeritus in 2009. Epel's research focused on fertilization and development in the marine environment, often using sea urchin gametes. He is the recipient of a Guggenheim fellowship, the Cox Medal for Excellence in Fostering Undergraduate Research at Stanford and the Ed Ricketts Memorial Award for Lifetime Achievement in the Marine Sciences, and is a Fellow of the American Association for the Advancement of Science and the California Academy of Sciences.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of the professional papers of Dr. David Epel, including correspondence with colleagues; administrative files from his tenure as acting dean of Stanford Universty's Hopkins Marine Station; lab notebooks; research files and drafts of published work; files on grants from the National Institute of Health, the National Science Foundation, and other funding sources; files on conferences attended; and lecture notes, syllabi, examples of student work, and other materials from courses taught by Epel.
Arrangement note
Files are arranged into ten series: correspondence; biographical/career; Hopkins Marine Station; Marine Biological Laboratory, Woods Hole; lab notebooks; grants; writing/research; events; courses; and restricted files.
Access Terms
Hopkins Marine Station--Curricula.; Hopkins Marine Station--Faculty.; Hopkins Marine Station; Developmental biology; Embryology; Sea urchins.
Collection Contents
- Correspondence, Series 1
  - General Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence re other papers (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, A-F, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, G-O, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 6-7)
  - Correspondence, P-Z, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 8-9)
  - Correspondence, A-E, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, F-J, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, K-O, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, P-S, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, T-Z, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, A-E, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, F-J, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, K-O, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, P-U, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, V-Z, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, A-E, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, F-K, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, L-P, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence, Q-T, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 25-26)
  - General Correspondence, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - General Correspondence, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - General Correspondence, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - General Correspondence, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - General Correspondence, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - General Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Miscelleaneous (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Petitions (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Correspondence and Clippings, DDT (Box 1, Folder 35-36)
  - Unfiled correspondence (Box 1, Folder 37-38)
  - Adair, Steve (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Aketa, Kenji (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Alberte, Randall (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Amor, Analia (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Babcock, Donner (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Baccetti, Baccio (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Barber, Richard T. (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Bard, Shannon (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Bavister, Barry D. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Baxter, Charles (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Bayer, Barbara (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Benovic, Adam (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Biggs, James (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Boletzky, Sigurd (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Brawley, Susan H. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Brewer, Peter (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Brismar, Kerstin (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Brown, George G. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Bruner, Barbara (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Buchanan, Bob (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Byrd, E. William (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Campanella, Chiara (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Carroll, Edward (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Chamberlain, John (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Chambers, Edward (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Chang, Donald C. (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Cherr, Gary N. (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Chow, Howard (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Christen, Richard (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Chung, Kiyon (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Ciapa, Brigitte (3 folders) (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Czihak, Gerhard (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Dale, B. (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - David, J. C. (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Davidson, Eric (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Deamer, David W. (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - De Laat, Siegfried W. (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Depledge (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Dirksen, Ellen R. (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Drozdov, Ashley (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Djerassi, Carl (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Dube, Francois and Louise Dufresne-Dube (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Ducci, Pilar (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Dunlap, Paul (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Ebert, Jim (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Ehrenstein, Gerald (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Ehrlich, Paul (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Elonson, Richard (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Epel, Berry (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Fennical, William (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Flavin, Martin (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Flannery, Brenden (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Fukumoto, M. (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Galgani, F. (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Garbers, David (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Gillies, Bob (Box 2, Folder 48-49)
  - Giudice, G. (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Gitler, Carlos (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Glaser, Rabbi Joseph (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Grainger, Jim (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Gottesman, Michael (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Gould, Meredith (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Hadfield, Michael (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Hanawalt, Phil (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Hand, Steve (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Harkey, Michael (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Hayes, Robin (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Hedrick, Jerry L. (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Herzenberg, Len (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Hiramoto, Yakio (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Hirose, Euichi (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Hofernann, Gretchen (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Hoshi, Motonori (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Human, Katie (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Humphreys, Thomas (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Irvine, Robert F. (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Iverson (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Iwamatsu, Takashi (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Jaffe, Laurinda (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Jagus, Rose (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Jamison, Curtis (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Jaynes, Chris (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Jeffrey, William R. (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - Johnson, Carl (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - Kalumuck, Karen (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Kanatani, H. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Kane, Robert (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Karmk, Naranjan (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Katajiri, Chiaki (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Katow, Hideki (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Katz, David (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Kaufman, Melissa (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Kim, John (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Kinsey, William (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Korn, Laurence (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Krause, Diane (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Kurelec, Branko (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Lambert, Charles (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Lanctot, Andrea (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Langston Labs (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Larochelle, Dennis (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Lauzon, Robert (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Lee, Hon Cheung (2 folders) (Box 3, Folder 19-20)
  - Levine, Laurence (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Longo, Frank (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Lopez, Kristin (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Lopo, Alina (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Manahan, Donal T. (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Marco, Roberto (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Mathews, Christopher K. (2 folders) (Box 3, Folder 27-28)
  - Matsuoka, Narimasa (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Mazia, Daniel (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - McCarty, Perry (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - McCullough, David H. (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Meijer, Laurent (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Metz, Charles (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Miles, Paul (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Mita, M. (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Mitteldorfs (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Mohri, Tatsuma (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Monahan, D. (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Monroy, Alberto (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Morrill, John B. (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Motokawe, Tatsuo (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Muchmore, Andrew (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Nakano, Eizo (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Nakazawa, Tohru (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Neyfakh, A. (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Nishioka, David (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Niu, M. C. (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Nuccitelli, Richard (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Oberdorf, John (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Pagano, G. (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Palazzo, Robert (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Palumbi, Stephen R. (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Panetta, Leon (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Paul, Miles (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Perry, George (Box 3, Folder 56-57)
  - Pigeon Point Hatchery (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Pittendrigh, Colin S. (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Poccia, Dominic (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Poenie, Martin (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Pogell, Burton M. (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Porzig, Ellen (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Price, Jenny (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Quatrano, Ralph (2 folders) (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Raffin, Thomas A. (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - Rainer, Julia (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - Rapraeger, Alan (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - Rees, Bernard (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - Renaud, Fernando L. (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - Reynolds, George (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Rinkevich, Buki (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Rosati, Floriana (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Roughgarten, Jonathan (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Rozengurt, Henry (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Sabbatical (3 folders) (Box 4, Folder 6-8)
  - Sano, Hideaki (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Sardet, Christian (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Sasaki, Hajime (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Sater, Amy (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Satoh, Noriyuki (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Schatten, Gerald (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Schmidt, Tobias (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Schomer, Beth (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Schuel, Herbert (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Schuetz, Allen W. (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Schulinder, Shimon (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Scott, Mike (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Seamon, Kenneth (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Segal, Sheldon (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Shapiro, Bennett (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Shen, Sheldon (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Shih, Yinghsien (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Shilling, Fraser (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Shur, Barry (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Sikora, Karol (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Da Silva, Pedro (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Silver, Robert (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Somero, George (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Spiegel, Melvin (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Sousa, Maria (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Spudich, James and Anna (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Stanton, R.C. (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Steinhardt, R.A. (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Stevens, Margaret (2 folders) (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Stipa, P. (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Strasser-Kaufman, K. (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Sund, Paul (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Swezey, Robert R. (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Tegner, Mia (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Terman, David (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Tilney, Lewis (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Toomey, Barbara Halland (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Vacquier, Victor D. (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Vale, Ron (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Vilar-Rojas, Cecelia (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Volcani, Benjamin (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - V'Orobov, Vladimir (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Walker, Bill (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Wang, Samuel (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Ward, Sam (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Wessel, Gary (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - Wessells, Norm (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Whittaker, Michael (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - Wickham, Jeff (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Williams, Lawrence (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - Willows, Dennis (Box 4, Folder 59)
  - Wilt, Fred (Box 4, Folder 60)
  - Winkler, Matt (Box 4, Folder 61)
  - Wolf, Don P. (Box 4, Folder 62)
  - Wourms, John (Box 4, Folder 63)
  - Xu Yin, Dong (Box 4, Folder 64)
  - Yanagimachi, R. (Box 4, Folder 65)
  - Yasumasu, Ikuo (Box 4, Folder 66)
  - Zhou, Jing (Box 4, Folder 67)
  - Zhu, Wei (Box 4, Folder 68)
  - Zimmerberg, Joshua (Box 4, Folder 69)
  - Ziomek, Carol (Box 4, Folder 70)
- Biographical/Career, Series 2
  - Annual Faculty Reports (Box 4, Folder 71-72)
  - Correspondence--jobs (Box 4, Folder 73)
  - Job offers (Box 4, Folder 74)
  - Correspondence re position at Stanford (Box 4, Folder 75)
  - Correspondence re move (Stanford to SIO) (Box 4, Folder 76)
  - Stanford/La Jolla correspondence (Box 4, Folder 77)
  - Sabbatical Leave (Box 4, Folder 78)
  - Johnson Foundation (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Merck (Box 5, Folder 2-3)
  - Patent matters (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Seminars, UC Biochem, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Seminars, AAAS Symposia, 1964 Dec (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - AAAS, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - AAAS talk (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Western Society of Malacologists, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Photographs -- electron microscope (Box 5, Folder 10-11)
  - HMS -- 1977 move (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - HMS renovation (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - HMS equipment (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Steel Professorship (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Permission for reproduction -- papers and figures (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Copyright releases (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Toho University (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Russia Trip (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Baja trip, Stanford Alumni Association Travel/Study Program (Box 5, Folder 20-21)
  - Baja (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Overseas Campuses (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Stanford Alumni Club, 1989 Feb 11 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Guggenheim (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - L'affaire "JDJ" (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Friday Harbor (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Churchill Overseas Fellowship (Box 5, Folder 28)
- Hopkins Marine Station, Series 3
  - Brochures (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Marine Station History (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - HMS history talk, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Alumni College (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Central California Consortium of Marine Labs (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Director, HMS, 1984-1986 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Friends of HMS/fundraising (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Dean's office, 1985-1986 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Dean, 1988-1989 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Library (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - MBL centennial (HMS recognition of) (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Monterey Bay Aquarium (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Monterey Bay Aquarium Research Institute (Box 5, Folder 41-42)
  - Monterey Bay Aquarium Research Institute / Stanford (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Monterey Bay Research (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Mazia, Daniel (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Mazia -- Japan Prize nomination (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Mazia -- Presidential Medal of Science nomination (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Mazia Lectureship (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Mazia papers (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Mazia Memorial Symposium (Box 5, Folder 50-51)
  - Abbotts Memorial Symposium, 1986-1987 (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Van Niel Memorial Lectureship (Box 5, Folder 53-54)
  - Marine Station visitors (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - American Society for Cell Biology Minority Affairs Committee (Box 5, Folder 56)
- Marine Biological Laboratory, Woods Hole, Series 4
  - MBL, embryology lectures, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - MBL, embryology course, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - MBL, embryology course, lab handouts, 1975-1976 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - MBL, 1980 summer (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Woods Hole Embryology Course Documents (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Fergap Program (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - MBL, Embryology, NSF Grant (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Lab Notebooks, Series 5
  - Lab notebook -- Elizabeth Baker, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Lab notebook -- David Epel, Res. Notes, 1960-1961 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Lab notebook -- David Epel, Research Data (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Protein Synthesis II, Oct-Dec 1966 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Inhibitors of Laminarinase Experiments (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Notebook, 4/4/1966 – 9/23/1966 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Laboratory Notebook (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Laboratory Notebook II (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Laboratory Notebook Duplicate Forms (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Dendraster, Summer 1967; G-G-P Formation, Laminarinase, DPN Kinase, Glycogen Phosphorylase (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Computation Book: D. Epel, Primarily conophore actuation, 15 Nov 1973 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Laminarinase assay methods (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - April 1, 1966 Notes (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Laboratory Notebook, 22 June - 4 October 1972 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Laboratory Notebook, October 27, 1969 - February 9, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Laboratory Notebook, November 13, 1970 - November 5, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Laboratory Notebook, November 16. 1971 - June 18, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Laboratory Notebook:, February 9, 1970 - June 18, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Computation Book 6: Elizabeth Baker - Dr. David Epel, 22 September 1974 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Friday Harbor Labs, Summer 1973 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Computation Book 5: Dr. David Epel, Elizabeth Baker, Ed Carroll, Rick Steinhardt, 3 August 1973 - 22 August 1974 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Computation Book - unlabelled (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Laboratory Notebook, 9/20/68 - 2/19/69 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Laboratory Notebook, 24 Jan 68 - 18 Apr 69 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Computation Book: Cortical Granules. David Epel and Elizabeth Baker, 4/28/71 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Laboratory Notebook, 7/5/68 - 10/30/68 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Laboratory Notebook, Jan - June 1969 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Laboratory Notebook, June 22, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Laboratory Notebook, 9 October 1972 - July 1973 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Laboratory Notebook: unlabelled (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Laboratory Notebook: unlabelled II (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Laboratory Notebook: Epel-Elliot-Bruner, July 29, 1969 - October 27, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Lab Notes, 9 May 1966-12 May 1966 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Lab Notes, 1/12/68 – 2/7/68 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - PH and resp. calculations, L. vaueagatus (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Laminarinase #2, Sept. 1967 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Book 1 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Book 2 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Book 3 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Book 4 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Book 5 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Book 6 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - George Sonnenborn Notebook (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Antarctica Notebook, Jan 1996 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Summer 91 MBL Lab (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Photo Negatives, "E6 Epel" (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Paul/Epel Labeled Notebook (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Berkeley Sabbatical Notebook (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Light-Scattering Data (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - L. Vauegatus (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Protein Synthesis, 4/66-10/66 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - pHi (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Protein Synthesis Notes, 1979-1984 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - DPN Kinase Experiments (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Micro-fluouinety, 6 March 1969 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - David Epel, Johnson Fdn. Notebook (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Notebook labeled IV (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Notebook labeled II (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - DPN Kinase, 19 Nov. 1965 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Experiments @ MBL - Woods Hole (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Pea Experiments (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - DPN Kinase II, 14 Jan 1966 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - L. vauegatus mela____ assays (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - S. purparatus, 30 March 1965 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Loose leaf Notes (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - George M. Sonnenborn Notebook (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - June 1965 (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Notebook labeled I (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Notebook labeled VI (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Notebook labeled V (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - Unlabeled blue notebook (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Laminarinase V, 4/15/68-5/22/68 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Parthoneogenesis and Fert. Inhibitor Experiments, 7 Nov. 1965 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Notebook labeled III (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Joshua B. Epel Notebook (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Re Calculations and derivations from experiment data (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Hopkins Marine Station, Feb 1, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Comparative Studies, March 2, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Specula Experiments, 6 July (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Fertilization and Cell Division (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Oogenesis (Box 9, Folder 11)
- Grants, Series 6
  - National Institutes of Health, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - National Institutes of Health grant, sea urchin eggs, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - National Institutes of Health grant, role of nitric oxide in fertilization (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - California Sea Grant Program, nitromusk compounds, 2002 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - California Sea Grant Program (Box 9, Folder 16-18)
  - National Science Foundation, education (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - National Science Foundation, 1986-1991 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - National Science Foundation, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - NO Patent (Box 9, Folder 22-25)
  - Biocomplexity grant (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Project grant, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Office of Naval Research workshop (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Office of Naval Research/HMS, etc. (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Office of Naval Research grant, "Into. of macromolecules…", 1990 (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Office of Naval Research grant (Box 9, Folder 31-32)
  - LMER proposal (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Scripps/HMS grant, 1976-1981 (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Grant proposals (Box 9, Folder 35-38)
  - Grant proposals (Box 9, Folder 1-2)
- Writing/Research, Series 7
  - Ideas (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - LJ research/ideas (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Ideas - sperm activation (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Ideas - ionic media for eggs (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Ideas - research discussions (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Ideas - micromeres and cleavage clock (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous ideas, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous ideas (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Research miscellany (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Baxter research (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Movie data (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - TEM experiments -- 21 Oct 1975 -- pH study (J.J.), nicotine (B. Byrd) (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - TEM experiments -- 20 Jul 1975 -- polyspermy after NH(3) treatment (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - TEM experiments -- 26 Jan 1976 -- NH(3) and Na (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - TEM experiments notebook, Elizabeth Baker (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Phosphorylase notes (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - A23187 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Cell cycle pH (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - CB/AAT (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - CB and transport (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Cytochalasin B (Box 10, Folder 23-24)
  - Amiloride notes (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Aune, Tom (Box 10, Folder 26-31)
  - Aune/Epel papers (Box 10, Folder 32-33)
  - Patton, Chris - Ems (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - Recent slides (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - H(2)O(2) (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - Microinjection (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - [Hajine?] (Box 10, Folder 38)
  - Schmidt and Epel / AAT and pressure (Box 10, Folder 39)
  - Humphreys/Epel research - NH(4) paper notes (Box 10, Folder 40)
  - Humphreys/Epel research - cordycepin (Box 10, Folder 41)
  - Polysomes (Box 10, Folder 42)
  - Collaborative work: Yanagamachi (Box 10, Folder 43)